Guide to the New England Church Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
New England Church Records
1640-2004
RG 48
Yale University Divinity School Library
23
(55 boxes)
Record Group 48 is an open collection composed of records from individual churches in the six New England states.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Material in this collection dates from 1640 to 2004.
Scope and Contents
At last revision, the collection comprised approximately 23 linear feet of material. A small portion of the material is in manuscript form while the majority is printed, including manuals, directories, news bulletins and historical papers. The churches are arranged alphabetically within each state with name changes and other historical data noted when pertinent. The material for each church is arranged chronologically except in a few cases where the quantity of material warranted a more detailed arrangement. Additional documentation regarding these churches may be available in the Library's cataloged collection.
Arrangement
I. Connecticut Churches
II. Maine Churches
III. Massachusetts Churches
IV. New Hampshire Churches
V. Rhode Island Churches
VI. Vermont Churches
Baptists -- New England -- History -- Sources; Church records and registers -- New England; Congregational churches -- New England -- History -- Sources; Lutheran Church -- New England -- History -- Sources; Methodist Church -- New England -- History -- Sources; Presbyterian Church -- New England -- History -- Sources; Connecticut -- Church history -- Sources; Maine -- Church history -- Sources; Massachusetts -- Church history -- Sources; New England -- Church history -- Sources; New Hampshire -- Church history -- Sources; New Haven (Conn.) -- Church history -- Sources; Rhode Island -- Church history -- Sources; Vermont -- Church history -- Sources; Catholic Church -- History -- Sources -- New England; Episcopal Church -- History -- Sources -- New England; Methodist Episcopal Church -- History -- Sources -- New England; United Church on the Green (New Haven, Conn.); United Church of Christ -- History -- Sources -- New England
- Connecticut Churches, Series I
  - Abington
    - Abington Church and Society, 1853 (Box 55)
  - Ansonia
    - Congregational Church, 1885 (Box 50)
    - First Methodist Church, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Ashford
    - Congregational Church, 1864 (Box 55)
  - Avon
    - Congregational Church, 1851, 1919 (Box 29)
  - Bethlehem
    - First Church of Christ, 1890 (Box 2)
  - Branford
    - Congregational Church, 1858, 1859 (Box 55)
    - Congregational Church, 1858 (Box 29)
    - First Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 29)
    - Trinity Church, 1882, 1920-1946 (Box 1)
  - Bridgeport
    - First Baptist Church, 1838 (Box 2)
    - First Congregational Church, 1876, 1895-1901 (Box 2)
    - Hungarian Evangelical and Reformed Church, 1944-1961 (Box 2)
    - Park Street Congregational Church, 1874-1913 (Box 2)
    - Park Street Congregational Church, 1943-1968 (Box 40)
    - St. Paul's Church, 1868 (Box 54)
    - Scandinavian Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 2)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1853 (Box 2)
    - South Congregational Church, 1892 (Box 2)
    - Stratfield and Newfield Parish (Box 55)
    - West End Congregational Church, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Brookfield
    - Congregational Church, 1876 (Box 54)
  - Brooklyn
    - Trinity Church / Old Trinity Church, 1858-1991 (Box 2)
  - Canton Center
    - Congregational Church, 1886 (Box 29)
  - Cheshire
    - First Congregational Church, 1870, 1906 (Box 29)
    - St. Peter's Church, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Chester
    - Congregational Church, 1892 (Box 2)
  - Clinton
    - First Church of Christ, 1867-1928 (Box 2)
  - Columbia
    - Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 54)
  - Cornwall
    - Second Congregational Church, 1877 (Box 55)
    - Coventry First Society, 1811 (Box 29)
  - Coventry
    - First Society (Box 55)
  - Danielson
    - Westfield Congregational Church, 1901, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Deep River
    - Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 2)
  - Derby
    - First Congregational Church, 1903, 1920 (Box 29)
    - St. James's Parish, 1891, 1896 (Box 2)
  - Durham
    - The Church of the Epiphany, 1912 (Box 54)
  - East Canaan
    - Congregational Church, 1902 (Box 29)
  - East Hampton
    - Congregational Church, 1898 (Box 29)
  - East Hartford
    - First Congregational Church, 1860, 1910-1913 (Box 2)
  - East Haven
    - First Congregational Church, 1876, 1892, 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - East Norwalk
    - Christ Church, 1940 (Box 2)
  - East Windsor
    - First Congregational Church, 1871-1902, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Third Congregational Church, 1842 (Box 2)
    - Congregational Church, 1953 (Box 48)
  - Enfield
    - First Congregational Church, 1899 (Box 50)
    - Strict Congregational Church, 1899 (Box 3)
  - Ellington
    - Congregational Church, 1896 (Box 29)
  - Essex
    - First Baptist, 1861, 1911, 1936 (Box 3)
    - St. John's Church, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Fairfield
    - Congregational Society of Green's Farms, 1911 (Box 3)
    - First Congregational Church of Christ, 1839, 1890, 1892-1914 (Box 3)
    - Greenfield Hill Church, 1932 (Box 30)
    - Prime Ancient Society, 1640-1890 (Box 50)
    - St. Paul's Episcopal Church, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Fair Haven
    - Second Congregational Church, 1876 (Box 55)
  - Falls Village
    - Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 3)
  - Farmington
    - Congregational Church, 1872, 1900 (Box 3)
  - Gilead
    - Congregational Church, 1878 (Box 30)
  - Goshen
    - Congregational Church, 1852 (Box 3)
  - Greenfield
    - Congregational Church, 1876 (Box 55)
  - Greenwich
    - Baptist Church, 1988 (Box 50)
    - First Congregational Church, 1879, 1895, 1908 (Box 30)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 3)
  - Groton
    - Congregational Church, 1877 (Box 55)
    - First Church of Christ, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Guilford
    - Christ Church, 1938, n.d. (Box 3)
    - First Congregational Church, 1893-1940 (Box 3)
    - Third Church, 1893 (Box 30)
  - Haddam
    - First Church of Christ, ca. 1934 (Box 49)
    - First Congregational Church, 1835, 1879, 1902 (Box 30)
  - Hadlyme
    - Congregational Church, 1876-1913 (Box 30)
  - Hamden
    - Congregational Church in Mt. Carmel, 1879, 1897 (Box 3)
    - Mt. Carmel Congregational Church, 1864 (Box 55)
    - Spring Glen Church, U.C.C., 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6a)
    - Whitneyville Congregational Church, 1876, 1895 (Box 3)
  - Hartford
    - Asylum Hill Congregational Church, 1906-1946 (Box 30)
    - Chiesa Evangelica Italiana, n.d. (Box 30)
    - Christ Church, 1879-1940 (Box 3)
    - Farmington Avenue Congregational Church, 1901 (Box 31)
    - First Church of Christ: General, 1835-1894 (Box 3)
    - FCC: General, 1895-1936 (Box 31)
    - FCC: Yearbook, 1897-1928 (Box 46)
    - First Ecclesiastical Society, 1670-1903 (Box 50)
    - First Presbyterian, 1875-1877 (Box 30)
    - Fourth Congregational Church, 1855, 1890 (Box 31)
    - Grace Episcopal Church, 1938 (Box 30)
    - North Church, 1839 (Box 30)
    - Park Congregational Church, 1914 (Box 30)
    - St. Paul's Methodist Church, 1904 (Box 30)
    - Second Congregational Church of Christ, 1870-1951 (Box 3, Box 49)
    - South Church, 1870 (Box 30)
    - Swedish Evangelical Lutheran Emmanuel Church, 1929 (Box 49)
    - Trinity Church, 1903-1906 (Box 3)
    - Unitarian Meeting House, 1967-1968 (Box 49)
    - Wetherfield Avenue Congregational Church, 1908 (Box 48)
  - Harwinton
    - Congregational Church, 1868-1908 (Box 31)
  - Holbrook
    - Winthrop Congregational Church, 1886 (Box 55)
  - Jewett City
    - Congregational Church, 1875 (Box 55)
  - Kensington
    - Congregational Church, 1904, 1912 (Box 4)
  - Killingworth
    - First Ecclesiastical Society, 1828 (Box 50)
    - Congregational Church, 1870 (Box 55)
  - Lebanon
    - First Church of Christ, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Lebanon Meeting House, 1939 (Box 50)
  - Ledyard
    - Congregational Church, 1859 (Box 55)
  - Litchfield
    - First Church of Christ, 1861-1931 (Box 4)
  - Madison
    - Congregational Church, 1878 (Box 55)
  - Mansfield Center
    - First Congregational Church, 1876 (Box 55)
    - Congregational Church, 1910 (Box 31)
  - Meriden
    - Center Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 31)
    - First Congregational Church, 1843-1906 (Box 31)
    - St. Rose's Church, 1898 (Box 31)
  - Middle Haddam
    - Christ Church, 1883-1895 (Box 4)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1873 (Box 54)
  - Middlebury
    - Congregational Church, 1896, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Middletown
    - Church of the Holy Trinity, n.d. (Box 4)
    - First Church of Christ, 1876 (Box 55)
    - First Congregational Church, 1837 (Box 4)
    - South Congregational Church, 1876-1947 (Box 42)
    - Universalist Church, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Milford
    - First Church of Christ Congregational, 1852, 1844-1945 (Box 4)
    - St. Peter's Episcopal Church, 1939 (Box 48)
  - Milton
    - Congregational Church, 1898 (Box 32)
  - Monson
    - First Church, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Mystic
    - Congregational Church, 1902 (Box 32)
  - Naugatuck
    - Congregational Church, 1851-1912 (Box 32)
    - Swedish Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1887-1917 (Box 51)
  - New Britain
    - Centre Church, 1876 (Box 55)
    - First Church of Christ, 1862 (Box 32)
    - St. Mark's Church, 1904 (Box 32)
    - South Congregational Church, 1869-1887 (Box 4)
    - Swedish Evangelical Bethany Church, 1935-1938 (Box 4)
  - New Canaan
    - Congregational Church, 1879 (Box 55)
    - St. Mark's Parish, 1939 (Box 4)
  - New Hartford
    - First Ecclesiastical Society, 1846 (Box 32)
  - New Haven
    - All Saints Chapel, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Benedict Memorial Church (see: First Presbyterian Church) (Box 53)
    - Bethany Chapel, 1868, n.d. (Box 4)
    - Calvary Baptist Church, 1871-1962, n.d. (Box 4)
    - Center Church (see: First Congregational Church) (Box 6, Box 27)
    - Chapel of St. Thomas More at Yale, 1938 (Box 48)
    - Chapel St. Congregational Church (named changed in 1871 to Church of the Redeemer) - see Record Group 266
    - Christ Church, 1859-1946 (Box 5)
    - Church of Christ in Yale University, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Church of the Ascension, 1939-1948 (Box 5)
    - Church of the Redeemer (formerly known as Chapel St. Congregational Church) - see Record Group 266
    - Church Street Church (see also Plymouth Congregational Church), 1843 (Box 5)
    - College Street Congregational Church (see also Plymouth Congregational Church), 1850-1875 (Box 5)
    - Davenport Congregational Church, 1863-1891 (Box 5)
    - Dixwell Avenue Congregational Church / United Church of Christ, 1938, 2010-2012 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dwight Place Congregational Church, 1873-1948 (Box 5)
    - First Baptist Church, 1823, 1850-1926 (Box 6)
    - First Congregational Church in Fair Haven (see also Grand Avenue Congregational Church), 1871-1889, 1980 (Box 6, Box 50)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven (aka Center Church): Manuals and Catalogues of members, 1847-1920 (Box 47)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: Manuals, 1921-1938 (Box 27)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: booklets and bulletins re. history of church and its meeting house, 1888-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: service bulletins, notices re. pastors, 1906-1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: reports, financial documentation, 1878-1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: correspondence regarding hiring of assistant pastor, 1905-1906 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: newsletter - "The Center Church Chronicle", 1916-1942 (Box 7)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: newsletter - "The Center Church Chronicle", 1943-1953 (Box 27)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: reports of Ladies' Home Missionary Society, 1864-1980 (Box 48)
    - First Church of Christ in New Haven: organizations and programs, incl. First Church Home for Aged Women, 1855-1921 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - First Methodist Episcopal Church: General, 1852-1926 (Box 28)
    - FMEC: General, 1939 (Box 8)
    - FMEC: Bound Volumes, 1876-1894 (Box 8)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Minutes of Session, 1886-1949 Apr (Box 52)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Minutes of Session, 1949 May- 1979 Sep (Box 53)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Minutes of Session, 1979 Oct - 2004 Jan (Box OV3)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Minutes of Session, 2004 January - 2009 May (Box OV3)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Worship service bulletins, 1960-1970 (Box OV3)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Mission Study Report (church survey), 1997 (Box OV3)
    - First Presbyterian Church: 4 audio cassette tapes related to Refugee Resettlement Project (Cambodia refugees sponsored by church), 1982-1990 (Box OV3)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Records of Service, 1885-1889 (Box 53)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Appeal for Building Funds, ca. 1904 (Box 53)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Constitution of Young People's Christian Endeavor Society (Box 53)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Notes on History of Church Gleaned from Session Minutes, n.d. (Box 53)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Financial Record Book of Women's Groups, 1954-1973 (Box OV1–OV2)
    - First Presbyterian Church: Financial Records, 1922-1987 (Box OV1)
    - First Universalist Church, 1933 (Box 8)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society of New Haven: books by Phebe Hanaford: Daughters of America; or Women of the Century (1882) and From Shore to Shore and Other Poems (1871), 1871, 1882 (Box OV4)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society: A Collection of Psalms and Hymns for the Use of Universalist Societies and Families by Hosea Ballou, 1840 (Box OV4)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society: Bound volume: "Record of the First Universalist Society" (1836-1870) (holograph) (Box OV4)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society: Bound volume: Records of the Prudential Committee, First Universalist Society (1870-1895) (holograph) (Box OV4)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society: Bound volume: Records of the Social Service Committee of Men's League, First Universalist Society (holograph), 1911 (Box OV4)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Society: Looseleaf notebook: transcripts and copies of historical documents, including: "Records of the First Universalist Society in New Haven (1836) (20 typed pages); "Historical Sketch of the First Universalist Church and Society in New Haven, Conn. (1873) by Phebe Hanaford (20 page pamphlet); "The History of the First Universalist Church" by Lucy Creemer Peckham (1911) (6 typed pages); "History of the Society" compile by Eunice K. Armstead (1936) (1 page); "The Finished Work; of Four Years in New Haven" a farewell sermon by Phebe Hanaford (1874) (14 page typed transcript); Additional histories, list of places of worship, list of ministers. (Box OV4)
    - Free Congregational Church (see also Plymouth Congregational Church), 1834 (Box 8)
    - Grace Church, 1886, 1892 (Box 8)
    - Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, 1889 (Box 9)
    - Grand Avenue Congregational Church (see also First Congregational Church in Fair Haven), 1898, 1904 (Box 9)
    - Grand Street Baptist Church, 1872 (Box 9)
    - Hope Baptist Church, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Howard Avenue Baptist Mission, 1890 (Box 9)
    - Howard Avenue Congregational Church: Misc., 1873-1901, n.d. (Box 40)
    - HACC: Howard Avenue Church News, 1891-1902, 1916 (Box 44–45)
    - Howe Street Church, 1845-46, 1868 (Box 9, Box 50)
    - New Haven Korean Church, 1992 (Box 49)
    - North Church (North Church united with Third Congregational Church in 1884 to form the United Church. North Church also referred to as the United Society.): General Materials, 1813-1884, n.d. (Box 9)
    - NC: re: Sunday School, 1833-1861 (Box 9)
    - NC: re: Sunday School, 1866-1883, 1930 (Box 10)
    - NC: re: Women's Organizations, 1814-1877, 1902 (Box 10)
    - NC: re: Women's Organizations, 1937, n.d. (Box 10)
    - NC: re: Youth Organizations, 1855-1876, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Oak Street Christian Parish, 1954-1956 (Box 10)
    - Park Street Church, 1838 (Box 10)
    - Pilgrim Congregational Church, 1949 (Box 10)
    - Plymouth Congregational Church (name changes: 1831-Missionary Church, 1832-Free Congregational Church, 1839-Church St. Church, 1848-College St. Church, 1895-Plymouth Congregational Church.), 1899-1935 (Box 10)
    - S. Faith's House, 1906 (Box 11)
    - St. James Church (Westville), 1872-1935, n.d. (Box 11)
    - St. James's Episcopal Church, 1905 (Box 11)
    - St. John's Church, 1871-1945 (Box 11)
    - St. John Street Methodist, 1878 (Box 11)
    - St. John Street Methodist Episcopal Church, 1878 (Box 11)
    - St. Luke's Church, 1894 (Box 11)
    - St. Mary's Church, 1889-1935 (Box 11)
    - St. Paul's Church: General, 1853-1899, 1945 (Box 11)
    - SPC: General, 1900-1915 (Box 12)
    - St. Thomas's Church, 1865-1928 (Box 12)
    - Second Congregational Church of Fair Haven, 1865-1902 (Box 12)
    - South Congregational Church, 1854-1866 (Box 12)
    - South Reformed Church, 1868 (Box 13)
    - Taylor Church, 1871 (Box 13)
    - Third Congregational Church (Third Church united with North Church in 1884 to form United Church): General material, 1841-1879 (Box 13)
    - TCC: re: Sunday School, 1857-1863 (Box 13)
    - TCC: re: Women's Organizations, 1866-1876 (Box 13)
    - TCC: re: Youth Organizations, 1869, 1883, n.d. (Box 13)
    - Trinity Church, 1814-1856, 1899 (Box 13, Box 50)
    - Trinity Church, 1900-1945 (Box 14)
    - Trinity Lutheran Church, 1937, 1946 (Box 14)
    - Trinity Methodist Episcopal Church, 1904 (Box 14)
    - United Church of New Haven (Formed in 1884 by union of North and Third Churches): General Materials, 1843-1944, n.d. (Box 14, Box 32)
    - UCNH: re: Sunday School, 1884-1925, n.d. (Box 15)
    - UCNH: re: Joint Sunday School with Center Church, 1930-1962 (Box 16)
    - UCNH: re: Men's Organizations, 1890-1942 (Box 16)
    - UCNH: re: Women's Organizations, 1891-1943, n.d. (Box 17)
    - UCNH: Bound Volumes, 1884-1923 (Box 17)
    - UCNH: Bound Volumes, 1909-1947 (Box 18)
    - UCNH: re: Youth Organizations, 1886-1935, n.d. (Box 19)
    - UCNH: Catalogues and Reports, 1886-1907 (Box 45)
    - West Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 20)
    - Westville Congregational Church, 1876-1900, 1923 (Box 20)
    - White-Haven Meeting House, 1813 (Box 50)
  - New London
    - First Church of Christ, 1901 (Box 20)
    - St. James Parish, 1847, 1890 (Box 20)
  - Newtown
    - Congregational Church, 1947 (Box 20)
    - Trinity Parish, 1882 (Box 20)
  - Norfolk
    - Church of Christ Congregational, 1896-1936, 1955, 1959 (Box 32)
  - North Branford
    - Congregational Church, 1850 (Box 55)
  - North Canaan
    - Pilgrim Church, 1887-1892 (Box 32)
  - North Coventry
    - Church of Christ, 1846 (Box 55)
    - Congregational Church, 1837 (Box 32)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1859 (Box 55)
  - North Haven
    - Congregational Church of Christ, 1832, 1901 (Box 20)
    - St. John's Parish, 1859, 1901-1934 (Box 20)
  - North Mansfield
    - Congregational Church, 1879 (Box 20)
  - North Milford
    - Congregational Church, 1879 (Box 20)
  - North Stonington
    - Congregational Church, 1848 (Box 49)
  - Northfield
    - Congregational Church, 1882-1887 (Box 33)
  - Northford
    - Northford Congregational Church, 1876, 1924-1950 (Box 28)
    - St. Andrew's Church, 1926, 1938 (Box 28)
  - Norwalk
    - First Church, 1829, 1868, 1902 (Box 20)
  - Norwich
    - Broadway Congregational Church, 1884-1915 (Box 33)
    - Central Baptist Church, 1865 (Box 55)
    - First Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 33)
    - Methodist Episcopal Churches, 1867 (Box 20)
    - Park Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1860, 1876, 1876 (Box 50)
  - Old Lyme
    - First Church, 1884-1910 (Box 33)
  - Old Saybrook
    - Congregational Church, 1885 (Box 33)
  - Plymouth
    - Congregational Church, 1985 (Box 54)
  - Pomfret
    - First Church of Christ, 1865 (Box 33)
  - Preston
    - First Congregational Church, 1900 (Box 33)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1889 (Box 54)
  - Prospect
    - Congregational Church, 1898, 1908 (Box 33)
  - Redding
    - First Church of Christ Congregational, 1882 (Box 28)
  - Ridgefield
    - First Congregational Church, 1882 (Box 32)
  - Rockville
    - Union Congregational Church of Christ, 1907 (Box 34)
  - Salisbury
    - Congregational Church: Misc., 1873-1920 (Box 20)
    - CC: _The Chronicle_, 1885-1921 (Box 44)
    - St. John's Church, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Saybrook
    - Deep River Baptist Church, 1870 (Box 34)
    - First Church of Christ, 1961 (Box 49)
  - Seymour
    - Congregational Church, 1883-1899 (Box 20)
    - Congregational Church, 1900-1922 (Box 34)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, 1892, 1895 (Box 34)
    - Trinity Church, 1894-1895 (Box 34)
  - Sharon
    - Christ Church, 1909 (Box 34)
  - Shelton
    - Church of the Good Shepherd, 1870 (Box 34)
  - South Norwalk
    - Congregational Church, 1897 (Box 40)
  - South Windsor
    - Wapping Congregational Church, 1902 (Box 21)
  - Southington
    - Baptist Church, 1873 (Box 21)
    - First Church, 1780-1828 (Box 50)
    - First Congregational Church, 1864 (Box 21)
  - Stafford
    - First Congregational Church, 1877 (Box 21)
  - Stamford
    - First Congregational Church, 1840-1935 (Box 34)
  - Stonington
    - First Congregational Church, 1862, 1874 (Box 21)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1835-1884 (Box 21)
  - Stratford
    - Christ Church, 1864-1939 (Box 21)
    - Congregational Church, 1881-1903 (Box 21)
    - First Ecclesiastical Society, 1885 (Box 50)
  - Suffield
    - First Congregational Church, 1858, 1869 (Box 21)
    - Second Baptist Church, 1905 (Box 21)
  - Terryville
    - Congregational Church, 1938 (Box 21)
  - Thompson
    - Church of Christ, 1826 (Box 50)
  - Torrington
    - Center Congregational Church (also known as Third Congregational or First Church of Christ), 1876-1900 (Box 21)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, 1884 (Box 54)
    - Congregational Church, 1869 (Box 21)
    - Congregational Church, 1880 (Box 21)
  - Trumbull
    - Congregational Church, 1880 (Box 55)
  - Vernon Center
    - Church at Vernon Center, 1827 (Box 54)
  - Wallingford
    - First Congregational Church, 1759, 1878 (Box 28)
    - St. Paul's Episcopal Church, 1894-1941
  - Washington
    - First Congregational Church, 1880, 1895-1910, 1941 (Box 28)
  - Waterbury
    - First Congregational Church, 1875-1910, n.d. (Box 34)
    - First Church, 1903 (Box 54)
    - St. John's Church, 1854-1907 (Box 21)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1905, 1927 (Box 21)
    - Third Church, 1893 (Box 34)
  - Watertown
    - Christ Church, 1890, 1917 (Box 34)
    - First Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 34)
  - West Hartford
    - Congregational Church, 1863 (Box 55)
  - West Haven
    - Christ Church, 1839, 1872-1888, n.d. (Box 21)
    - First Congregational Church, 1923-1944 (Box 21)
    - First Congregational Church, 1851, 1863 (Box 35)
    - First Methodist Episcopal Church, 1916 (Box 21)
    - St. Paul's Church, 1940 (Box 34)
  - Westbrook
    - Congregational Church, 1876, 1876, 1894 (Box 34)
  - Weston
    - Norfield Congregational Church, 1898 (Box 34)
  - Westport
    - Congregational Church, 1883 (Box 49)
    - Saugatuck Congregational Church, 1907 (Box 54)
  - Westville
    - Congregational Church, 1886 (Box 34)
  - Wethersfield
    - Congregational Church, 1911-1935 (Box 35)
    - First Church of Christ, 1968-1969 (Box 49)
    - Wethersfield Methodist Episcopal Church, 1882 (Box 35)
  - Whitneyville
    - Whitneyville Church, 1877 (Box 55)
  - Willington
    - Congregational Church, 1875 (Box 35)
  - Windham
    - Congregational Church, 1900 (Box 35)
  - Windsor
    - First Church, 1930 (Box 35)
  - Winsted
    - First Congregational Church, 1844, 1897 (Box 21)